Lennon Alberto dos Santos

Backend Software Developer

LocationCuritiba, PR, BrazilEmaillennonalberto@gmail.comPhone+55 41 98821 4090Linkedinlinkedin.com/in/lennonalberto/Sitelennonalberto.github.ioGithubgithub.com/lennonalberto/

Fast learning and organized computer programmer with 5 years experience in diverse array projects of different areas, dedicated in creating a quality product for the end user. Highly experienced in .Net back-end development and SQL databases. Agile and helpful when working in team environments but also focused and independent when needed. Willing to learn new skills in both web development and design.

Experience

Systems Development Analyst

04/2018 - Present

Instituto das Cidades Inteligentes - Curitiba, Brazil

- Worked on over 5 projects that provide smart solutions for the city's Town Hall services.
- Implemented, tested and debugged back-end API's for mobile applications in C#/Asp.Net Core.
- Integrated services with third party APIs (e.g. Google Maps).
- Developed queries (Procedures, Views, Etc.) in SQL server.
- Built and configured a Chatbot app and Webhook API for Google Assistant using DialogFlow.
- Participated in Scrum based development, with daily meetings (standup) and two week sprints.

Backend Developer 12/2017 - 02/2018

Neomode - Curitiba, Brazil

- Developed back-end API for mobile applications for e-commerce mobile apps.
- Programmed the integration with cloud commerce and payment gateway APIs.

Computer Programmer

07/2013 - 08/2017

MPS Informática - Curitiba, Brazil

- Maintained and developed new functionalities in Microsoft Dynamics AX ERP system.
- Developed and maintained Delphi 7 and Asp. Net software for health insurance and financial organizations.
- Developed queries (Procedures, Views, Etc.) in SQL server.
- Communicated directly with client to address new requirements and problems.

Education

Bachelor in Computer Science

08/2009 - 08/2015

Languages

Universidade Federal do Paraná - Curitiba, Brazil

Technology Summary

LanguagesC, C#, Javascript, HTML, CSSPortugueseNative

Frameworks Asp.Net (Standard and Core), Entity Framework, NodeJS English Advanced

Databases SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDb

Other UML, Office suite